(+505) 8878 - 3068 [tigo] 8729 - 6778 [claro]

farinahdez@gmail.com

Vicky Jeanette Fariña Hernández

Contact

Address:

Urbanization Villa Miracles House E-22. From the school an appointment with God 2 c, to the South. 2c, Top. 75 vrs, to the North.



ID #: 001 - 230577 -0064B

Profile

I am a Systems Engineer with 15 years of experience in my profession and other areas such as: teaching; graphic designer; web designer; IT consultant and Digital Marketing advisor. I have knowledge and skills with computer technology tools (including TICs) in the areas in which I have worked as an engineer, teacher and designer. My expectations are to specialize in the area of web and mobile application development, with the aim of contributing my technological knowledge to education; among other areas that require digital transformation. I have an Adobe Certified Associate in Visual Communication using Adobe Photoshop CS6.0 Certification. I am in constant training on the Google Academy and Facebook & Meta platforms; in addition to updates in online courses from the platforms (MOOC): Digital Ad Expert, Udemy, Coursera, Hubspot, Audacity, Edutin, Open BootCamp, Codigo Facilito, MiriadaX. And I have participated in the DreamBuilder AWE Nicaragua program

Experience

ALFA - Digital Services (2017 - 2024)

Freelancer Job

- Graphic Design Advertising: Agendas, Banners, Brochures, Calendars, Catalogs, Packaging, Labels, Flyers, Logos, eBooks, Magazines, Cards.
- Website Design: HTML5 / CSS3 / JS5 / Bootstrap; PHP / MySql; WordPress (CMS).
- Web and Mobile Application Design: HTML5, App Inventor y Scratch.
- Teacher in Digital Marketing: Branding; Positioning SEO; Inbound Marketing; Socials Media; Email Marketing; Content Marketing; Display Advertising.

Polytechnic University of Nicaragua - UPOLI (2015) / Nicaraguan University of Science and Technology – UCYT (2013 – 2014)

University Professor

- Programming I (C++ Language) TUTORIAL
- Introduction to Computing,
- Data Structures and Algorithms I and II,
- Data Communication I and Computer Networks II,
- Website Design and Graphic Design,
- Database I (MS Access),
- Database II (MS SQL Server),
- Programming I (Visual Studio),
- Programming II (MS SQL Server with Visual Basic).

Nicaraguan Center for Computerized Studies - CECNIC (2008 – 2012)

Graphic Designer – Computer Science Teacher

- Design and Print the Advertising of the Company
- Microsoft Windows & Office Instructor.
- Graphic Design Tools Instructor (Adobe Suite CS6 and CorelDRAW12).

Institute of Computing and Commerce ICCSA - Sydicom (2003 – 2007)

Computer Science Teacher

- Microsoft Windows & Office
- Basic Accounting and Cash Management Techniques
- Graphic Design Tools (Adobe Suite and CorelDRAW12).

SKILLS

Systems engineering **Computer Science** Graphic design Web design Web Apps design **Animations**

Digital Marketing

MS Windows & Office

Adobe Suite CS6

COMPUTER SCIENCE & DESIGN

GIMP 2.0 CorelDRAW HTML5 / CSS3 / JS5 App Inventor 2 Scratch WordPress (CMS) Canva PHP / MySQL

DIGITAL MARKETING

Branding SEO **Inbound Marketing** Socials Media **Email Marketing Content Marketing**

Center for Research and Health Studies CIES – UNAN Managua (2000 – 2002)
Project IT Consultant

- Human resources and payroll system
 - ✓ Formulation, Analysis, Design and Implementation of the System.
 - ✓ Microsoft Project 2000 Teacher
- Management of the NLM Virtual Library

Applications and Systems, S.A. - ASSA & MERINCO (1997 – 2000)

IT Consultant for Applications and Systems

- Analyst Designer of Administrative Financial and Accounting Systems
 - ✓ Technical Documenter
- Technical Support for Administrative, Financial and Accounting Systems
- Teacher of Administrative, Financial and Accounting Applications and Systems

Educations

* MOOC Udemy (Mode Online)

https://udemy.com

COURSES	DATE
Professional Web Designer. From Intermediate to Expert	January 2024
UX Design + THML5 and CSS3 Easy and Practical!	January 2024
Create your own Games with HTML and Canvas Javascript	January 2024
Creating Video Games with Scratch	January 2024
Basic Digital Marketing for Entrepreneurs	Dec. 2023
Facebook Ads for Beginners: Create Facebook Ads	Dec. 2023
Facebook Pages: Create a Facebook Page for your Business	Dec. 2023
Program Android Applications with App Inventor	Dec. 2023

MOOC Digital Ad Expert (Mode Online)

https://learn.digitaladexpert.com

COURSES	DATE
Digital Marketing Course (currently)	January 2024

MOOC HubSpot Academy (Mode Online)

https://app.hubspot.com

COURSES	DATE
Digital Marketing (currently)	January 2024
Social Media Marketing Certification (currently)	January 2024
Inbound Sales (currently)	January 2024

MOOC Coursera (Mode Online)

https://www.coursera.org

COURSES	DATE
Introduction to Front-End Development	January 2024
Robotics	January 2024
Successful Business Management for PYMES	January 2024

Video Marketing
Display Marketing

Google Ads

Facebook Ads



INTERESTS

- Technological Trends
- Crafts and Recycling
- Entrepreneurship
- ✓ Music
- ✓ Environment
- Animal world

LANGUAGES

Spanish Engli



VOLUNTEERING

✓ Innovation Center

Zamora Teran Foundation

XO Repair (11 de January del 2020)

✓ Humboldt Nicaragua Center Graphic designer (May – July 2019)

REFERENCES

Lic. Enid Calvo Cascante
Director of Commercial Services at
Gurunet, Costa Rica.
(+506) 8842 – 1528

Lic. Wyvonne E. Bent Miller
Customer Service Agent for
Commerce Companies, Nicaragua.
(+505) 7678 – 5588

Ing. Randolph Cortez Systems engineer (+505) 8434 – 6977

MOOC MiriadaX (Mode Online)

https://miriadax.net

COURSES	DATE
FrontEnd development with HTML, CSS and Javascript	January 2024
Design Thinking: Creating successful products	January 2024

* MOOC Codigo Facilito (Mode Online)

https://codigofacilito.com

COURSES	DATE
Course to create Platform Game in HTML5	July 2022
Course to create Ship Game in HTML5	July 2022

MOOC Facebook BluePrint & Meta BluePrint (Mode Online)

https://trainingworkshops.facebookblueprint.com

COURSES	DATE
100-101: Meta Certified Digital Marketing Associate	July 2021
Online Course for Community Managers	May 2021

The Business Builder for Women - AWE (August - November 2021)

Platform: DreamBuilder Program

Program American Spaces – CCNN (12 – 25 November 2021)

Practical Workshop: Marketing and Communication Plan

Center for Multimedia Studies - D'GRAPHICS ADOBE CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE & CERTIPORT (May – August 2014)

Visual Communication using Adobe Photoshop ® CS6.0

University of Technology and Commerce – UNITEC (2007 – 2011)

Systems Engineer (University Career)